Guide to the Danny Everitt collection, 1967-2018 MS 862
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Danny Everitt collection
1967-2018
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Everitt, Danny
MS 862
3 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
17.4 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0862aip_001 (17.4 GB)
0.023 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0862aip_002 (0.023 GB)
1.51 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0862aip_003 (1.51 GB)
This collection consists of physical and digital material documenting the music career of Danny Everitt.
Biographical / Historical
Growing up in Victoria, TX, Danny Everitt connected with music from an early age. Like others in his age group, he joined bands in middle and high school. Upon graduation, he attended the University of Texas and studied Radio, Television, and Film.
During his time at UT, he joined the band Dogfood. After graduation, he moved to Nashville to start his music career. While touring, he entered the Kerrville Folk Festival New Folk contest and became one of the winners of 1976.
Hearing about the music scene in Houston, Everitt eventually relocating there. He played both solo and in a variety of bands including the Danny Everitt Band and Danny Everitt and the Rhythm Tramps. Until the early 1980s he played in and around Houston and temporarily relocated to California.
Within the 1980s and 1990s, Everitt lived in Austin and the Nashville-area. He moved back to Houston in the late 1990s and has lived in or near the city fver since. Over the years, he has released a number of albums including "Fire Down Inside," "Acoustic Guitar," and "Dream Big."
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of physical and digital material documenting the music career of Danny Everitt. The physical material includes song lyrics, fliers, posters, correspondence, and photographs. The digital material includes digital images and an oral history.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Request access to this digital material (stored on Fondren Library's nearline / non-public server) by contacting Woodson Research Center staff at woodson@rice.edu. Please use the Identifier number in your request.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Items donated by Danny Everitt from 2017 to 2019.
Related Materials
Please see audio in the KTRU Radio records, UA 011.
Index Terms
Subjects
Folk music -- Texas -- Houston; Music
Document Types
Folk music; Folk-rock music
- Series I: General Files
  - Art, 1982-2015 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Awards, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Backstage passes, 1982-2015 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Buddy magazine, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Business cards, 1970-2010 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Business records, 1975-2010 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Calendar, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Contacts, 1974-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Contracts, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1973-2008 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - publishing and copyright, 1981-1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - song pitches, 1977-2008 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dream Big, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ephmera, 1975-2018 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Fliers, 1974-2018 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Hank", 1976-09 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Kerrville Folk Festival, 1972-1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Lyrics - A - C, 1970-2010 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Lyrics - D - G, 1970-2010 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Lyrics - H - L, 1970-2010 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Lyrics - M - O, 1970-2010 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Lyrics - P - S, 1970-2010 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Lyrics - T - Y, 1970-2010 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Music review, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - News clippings, 1970-2010 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Notebook, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Promotional materials, 1972-1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Scrapbook pages, 1970-1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Set lists / song lists, 1970-2010 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Song critiques, 1976-1996 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Studio notes, 1970-2012 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Tickets, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Series II: Photographs
  - Page proofs, 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Photographs, 1970-2018 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Danny Everitt images, 1970-2017
    Scope and Contents
    Contents include low quality jpg images of Danny Everitt and his bands.
- Series III: Audio and Video
  - Sub-Series A: Danny Everitt audio
    - Austin album (reel-to-reel), 1971 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Dimes' Worth," "Deserted Island Blues," "Rhumba Song (La La La)," "Go!," "Blue Texas Mornin'" - Acme, "Changes," "Half Is Spent Alone," "Love Me for Me," "Did You See Her Face," "Numbered Days," "Truth Lies"
    - Danny live (cassette tape), 1973-12-16-1974-08-02 (Box 2)
      Contents include: WPGU - Emerald City Radio; Writing in Nashville - Live in Jackson
    - Danny Everitt and Mark McKinnon material (reel-to-reel), 1976-04-08 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Blue Texas Morning," "Dimes Worth of Answers," "No More," "Deserted Island Blues," "Good Times Buddies"
    - Theodore's / Steamboat (cassette tape), 1976-07-01 (Box 2)
      Contents include: Danny Everitt Band, Shake Russell, Rick Gordon
    - Corky's live (cassette tape), 1977 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Barefootin'," "Devil Woman," "What Shall I Do," "Sunset Highway," "Buick 6," "Stars," "It's Over"
    - Danny Everitt solo set (cassette tape), 1978-07-11 (Box 2)
      Contents include: Theodore's solo set: "Second Cup of Coffee," "Suzanne," "Mornin' Comes," "Best Friend," "Someone Stand Beside You," "Willow Tree," "Old Man," "I Miss Her"
    - Danny Everitt Band (cassette tape), 1978-07-29 (Box 2)
      Contents include: Theodores
    - Danny Everitt (cassette tape), 1978 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Stayed Too Long," "Rosalie," "It's Over," "Slipping Away," "Easy Way," "No More"
    - Danny Everitt - Dallas (cassette tape), 1980-10-09-1980-10-12 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Cold Wind/Cold Rain," "Here With Me," "My Son," "What Shall I Do," "Spare Me," "When the Stars Come Out," "I Heard a Rumour," "What Was It," "River Song," "From Out of Nowhere," "I Don't Care Anymore," "Lady Million," "One Good Chance," "It's Over Again," "Easy Way," "Sunset Highway," "(Is There) Anymore Gold"
    - Danny Everitt (cassette tape), 1980 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Morning Always Comes," "No More," "Hands on the Wheel," "Fire Down Inside," "What Was It," "One Good Chance," "It's Over Again," "Easy Way," "Stars," "Lady Million," "I Heard a Rumor," "Cold Wind/Cold Rain," "Stayed Too Long," "Rosalie," "Sunset Highway," "Slipping Away"
    - Danny Everitt demo (cassette tape), 1980 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Cold Wind/Cold Rain," "Lady Million," "No More," "I Heard a Rumour," "When the Stars Come Out," "Closer to You"
    - The Roosters - The Pelican Club (cassette tape), 1981-11-06 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Closer to You," "Lady Million," "Before You Accuse Me," "I Heard a Rumor," "Take Me to the River," "Fire Down Inside," "Hands on the Wheel," "Susan," "Morning Always Comes," "On Pretty Woman"
    - "Fire Down Inside" (2 - 12" LPs), 1981 (Box 2)
    - Songs by Terry Wilson and Danny Everitt (cassette tape), 1982 (Box 2)
    - Riverton Studio demo (cassette tape), 1983-04-29 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Two More Lovers," "One Step Ahead," "Can't Wait," "It Feels Good to Me," "One Step Ahead," "Can't Wait"
    - Riverton (cassette tape), 1983 (Box 2)
    - Danny Everitt (cassette tape), 1984-07-01 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Can't Wait," "Love Is for All Times," "How Do We Get By"
    - L.A sessions (reel-to-reel), 1984-07-01 (Box 2)
    - Danny Everitt - Hollywood (cassette tape), 1984-08 (Box 2)
    - Olympic tapes (cassette tape), 1984 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "I Trusted You," "You're the One," "Bossa Nova Bar-B-Q," "Don't Shoot," "One Step Ahead"
    - Danny Everitt (cassette tape), 1995 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "When the Stars Come Out," "We Can't Stop Now," "Almost Perfect"
    - Danny Everitt (cassette tape), 1995 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "When the Stars Come Out," "We Can't Stop Now," "Almost Perfect," "What Was It"
    - Taylor Sound (cassette tape), 1997-07-25 (Box 2)
      Contents include: "A Long Time Ago," "Easing Back," "Old Man in the Pier," "Lay Eyes on You Again"
    - 2nd demo (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Stayed Too Long" - Jubilee Studio, "Rosalie," "It's Over," "Slipping Away," "Easy Way," "No More"
    - Black tape (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "My Son," "What Shall I Do," "River Song," "I Heard a Rumour," "I Don't Care Anymore," Ballad of the Snow Leopard," "Nuke the Whales," "
    - Blue Texas Morning (cassette tape) (Box 2)
    - Combine master (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Dimes Worth of Answers," "No More," "Good Time Buddies," "Listen to the Singer"
    - Comedy of Errors (cassette tape) (Box 2)
    - Criterion (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: work tape, "When She Finally Takes You There"
    - Danny Everitt (8-track tape) (Box 2)
    - Danny Everitt (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "What Was It," "Almost Perfect," "I Heard a Rumor," "Hands on the Wheel," "Stayed Too Long," "Fire Down Inside," "Morning Always Come"
    - Danny Everitt (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Love Is for All Times"
    - Danny Everitt songs (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Blue Texas Morning"
    - Danny Everitt songs (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: Side A: "Blue Texas Morning," "Dimes Worth of Answers," "Is There Anymore Gold," "Good Times Buddies," "Undo What I Did," "Stayed Too Long," "Rosalie," "Nothing Better," "Slipping Away," "Lady Million"; Side B: "Fire Down Inside," "Morning Comes," "Hands on the Wheel," "Bossa Nova Bar-B-Q," "Can't Wait," "Two More Lovers," "Precious Knight," "I Trusted You," "Lady Blue," "Love Is For All Times"
    - Danny Everitt songs (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Love Is for All Time," "Dimes' Worth," "Bossa Nova Bar-B-Q," "Can't Wait," "Two More Lovers," "Lady Blue," "Hands on the Wheel," "Don't Take Your Love from Me," "Almost Perfect"
    - Danny Everitt songs (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Blue Texas Morning," "Dimes Worth of Answers," "Is There Anymore Gold," "Good Time Buddies," "Undo What I Did," "Stayed Too Long," "Rosalie," "Nothing Better," "Slipping Away," "Lady Million," "Fire Down Inside," "Morning Comes," "Hands on the Wheel," "Bossa Nova Bar-B-Q," "Can't Wait," "Two More Lovers," "Precious Knight," "I Trusted You," "Lady Blue," "Love Is for All Times"
    - Danny's tape (cassette tape) (Box 2)
    - Everitt (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Rosalie," "When She Finally Takes You There," "Morning Comes," "Hands on the Wheel," "Listen to the Singer," "Summer Apart," "The Shape You're In," "No More," "Old Man in the Pier," "Undo What I Did," "Slipping Away," "It's Over," "Easy Way"
    - Evertitt/McKinnon Retrospective (cassette tape) (Box 2)
    - Final mix (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Can't Wait," "Love Is for All Times," "How Do We Get By," "Thieves"
    - Master Mix II (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Gotta Get Back to You," "I Don't Care Anymore," "Maybe in the Morning," "Daydreams," "Can't Wait," "Love Is for All Times," "How Do We Get By," "I Heard a Rumor," "When The Stars Come Out," "Nothin' Better," "Closer to You"
    - Maxell (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Red Young," "Daydream," "Doran," "I Wrote that Song," KRNN interview S.G.S.A.
    - Roughs mix down (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "Can't Wait," "One Step Ahead"
    - Songs by Danny Everitt/T. Wilson (cassette tape) (Box 2)
      Contents include: "One Step Ahead," "Meltdown," "Can't Wait," "Love Is for All Times"
    - The Danny Everitt Band live at Texas Opry House (CD), 1978-05-25 (Box 3)
      Contents include: master wav files and access mp3 files.
    - Danny Everitt Band live at Texas Opry House (CD), 1978-05-25 (Box 3)
    - Danny Everitt Band live at Theodore's (2 CDs), 1978-07-29 (Box 3)
    - The Volume Dealers - Dad Was Right (CD), 1998 (Box 3)
    - The Volume Dealer at Satellite Lounge (CD), 1999-11-07 (Box 3)
    - Danny Everitt - Cold Wind Cold Rain (CD), 2007 (Box 3)
    - Houston Association of Acoustic Musicians compilation (CD), 2008 (Box 3)
    - Danny Everitt - Acoustic Souvenir (CD), 2013 (Box 3)
      Contents include: master wav files and access mp3 files. Tracks include: "Sunset Highway," "Old Man on the Pier," "When the Stars Come Out," "Dimes Worth," "What Was It," "I've Got Nothing," "Devil Woman," "Nothing But Everything," "The Ballad of Aubrey Call," "We Can't Stop Now."
    - Danny Everitt songs (CD) (Box 3)
    - Dogfood - The Pepper-Tanner Sessions (CD) (Box 3)
    - Fire Down Inside (CD) (Box 3)
    - Master 20 song set list (CD) (Box 3)
    - Rosalie recorded at KLOL (2 CDs) (Box 3)
  - Sub-Series B: Danny Everitt video
    - The Danny Everitt Band / The Rhythm Tramps (DVD), 1981 (Box 3)
    - Everitt-Saunders live (DVD), 2012 (Box 3)
    - Oral history, 2017-10-19
      These born digital video files consist of one master copy mov and one access copy located at scholarship.rice.edu.
    - Danny and Brian live at the Corner Pub (DVD) (Box 3)
    - Danny and Jack (DVD) (Box 3)
    - Demo Master (DVD) (Box 3)
    - Shake Russell and Danny Everitt live at Dominion (DVD) (Box 3)
    - Shoulder to the Stone (DVD) (Box 3)
    - Unitunes [?] (2 DVDs) (Box 3)
  - Sub-Series C: Other audio
    - Shake Russell - "Silverheart" / "Temper, Temper" (45 - 7" LP), 1975 (Box 3)
    - Bill and Bonnie Hearne - "I Ain't the Kind" / "The Last Thing I Needed" (45 - 7" LP), 1976 (Box 3)
    - John Vandiver (cassette tape), 1977-11-10-1983-03-11 (Box 3)
      Contents include: Live at Waco Hall: "Yonder Comes the Blues," "You Don't Have to Go," "So Different Blues," "Memories of You"; Live at Lone Star Bar: "Lover's Prayer," "Winnie the Wailer," "Chicken Fried Steak," "West TX Highway," "Deep in the West," "Cake Walk," "Make Your Move," "Try, "Oh Baby," "Country Girl," "Gypsy Songman," "Tomorrow Is a Long Time," "Friend to Me Too," Guest Singer, "Georgia"
    - Blaze Foley - "If I Could Only Fly" / "Let Me Ride in Your Big Cadillac" (45 - 7" LP), 1979 (Box 3)
    - Loose Change - Bell Session (cassette tape), 1980-04-10 (Box 3)
      Contents include: "Anymore Gold," "No More," "It's Over," "What Shall I Do," "I Don't Care Anymore," "River Song," "Snow Leopard"
    - Che Blammo (33 1/3 - 7" LP), 1981 (Box 3)
    - The Animals - "Love Is for All Time" / "It's Too Late" (45 - 7" LP), 1983 (Box 3)
    - Precious Knight demo - T. James (cassette tape), 1986 (Box 3)
    - Lynn Jones (cassette tape), 1987 (Box 3)
    - Terry Wilson (cassette tape), 2002-05-20 (Box 3)
    - Daydream demo (cassette tape) (Box 3)
    - Demis - Take My Hand (cassette tape) (Box 3)
    - Mark David McKinnon demo (2 reel-to-reels) (Box 3)
    - Shake Russell - Let Love Be True (CD) (Box 3)
- Series IV: Oversize Materials
  - Posters, 1970-1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Posters, 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Posters, 1990-1999 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Posters, 2000-2017 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Blaze film poster (removed from collection by donor), 2018